Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

WSLC is the Windows Subsystem for Linux Container CLI tool. It enables management and interaction with WSL containers from the command line.

Usage: wslc  [<command>] [<options>]

The following commands are available:
  container  Manage containers.
  image      Manage images.
  network    Manage networks.
  registry   Manage registry credentials.
  settings   Open the settings file in the default editor.
  system     System-level commands
  volume     Manage volumes.
  attach     Attach to a container.
  build      Build an image from a Dockerfile.
  create     Create a container.
  exec       Execute a command in a running container.
  export     Export a container's filesystem as a tar archive.
  images     List images.
  import     Import an image from a tarball.
  inspect    Inspect objects.
  kill       Kill containers.
  list       List containers.
  load       Load images.
  login      Log in to a registry.
  logout     Log out from a registry.
  logs       View container logs.
  pull       Pull images.
  push       Upload an image to a registry.
  remove     Remove containers.
  rmi        Remove images.
  run        Run a container.
  save       Save images.
  start      Start a container.
  stats      Display container resource usage statistics.
  stop       Stop containers.
  tag        Tag an image.
  version    Show version information.

For more details on a specific command, pass it the help argument. [-?]

The following options are available:
  -v,--version  Show version information for this tool
  -?,--help     Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Manage the lifecycle of WSL containers, including creating, starting, stopping, and removing them.

Usage: wslc container [<command>] [<options>]

The following sub-commands are available:
  attach   Attach to a container.
  create   Create a container.
  exec     Execute a command in a running container.
  export   Export a container's filesystem as a tar archive.
  inspect  Inspect a container.
  kill     Kill containers.
  logs     View container logs.
  list     List containers.
  prune    Remove all stopped containers.
  remove   Remove containers.
  run      Run a container.
  start    Start a container.
  stats    Display container resource usage statistics.
  stop     Stop containers.

For more details on a specific command, pass it the help argument. [-?]

The following options are available:
  -?,--help  Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Manage container images, including building, pulling, listing, and removing them.

Usage: wslc image [<command>] [<options>]

The following sub-commands are available:
  build    Build an image from a Dockerfile.
  remove   Remove images.
  inspect  Inspect images.
  list     List images.
  load     Load images.
  import   Import an image from a tarball.
  prune    Remove unused images.
  pull     Pull images.
  push     Upload an image to a registry.
  save     Save images.
  tag      Tag an image.

For more details on a specific command, pass it the help argument. [-?]

The following options are available:
  -?,--help  Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Lists images.

Usage: wslc images [<options>]

The following options are available:
  -f,--filter  Filter output based on conditions provided
  --format     Output formatting (json or table) (Default: table)
  --no-trunc   Do not truncate output
  -q,--quiet   Outputs the container IDs only
  --verbose    Output verbose details
  -?,--help    Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Removes containers.

Usage: wslc remove [<options>] <container-id>

The following command aliases are available: delete rm

The following arguments are available:
  container-id    Container ID

The following options are available:
  -f,--force      Delete containers even if they are running
  -?,--help       Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Removes images.

Usage: wslc rmi [<options>] <image>

The following arguments are available:
  image       Image name

The following options are available:
  -f,--force  Delete images even if they are being used
  --no-prune  Do not delete untagged parents
  -?,--help   Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Runs a container. By default, the container is started in the foreground; use --detach to run in the background.

Usage: wslc run [<options>] <image> [<command>] [<arguments>...]

The following arguments are available:
  image             Image name
  command           The command to run
  arguments         Arguments to pass to container's init process

The following options are available:
  --cidfile         Write the container ID to the provided path
  --cpus            Number of CPUs (e.g. 0.5, 1, 2.5)
  -d,--detach       Run container in detached mode
  --dns             IP address of the DNS nameserver in resolv.conf
  --dns-option      Set DNS options
  --dns-search      Set DNS search domains
  --domainname      Container domain name
  --entrypoint      Specifies the container init process executable
  -e,--env          Key=Value pairs for environment variables
  --env-file        File containing key=value pairs of env variables
  --gpus            Add GPU devices to the container ('all' to pass all GPUs)
  -h,--hostname     Container host name
  -i,--interactive  Attach to stdin and keep it open
  -l,--label        Set metadata on an object
  -m,--memory       Memory limit (e.g. 512M, 1G)
  --name            Name of the container
  --network         Connect a container to a network
  --network-alias   Add a network-scoped alias for the container
  -p,--publish      Publish a port from a container to host
  -P,--publish-all  Publish all exposed ports to random host ports
  --rm              Remove the container after it stops
  --shm-size        Size of /dev/shm (e.g. 64M, 1G)
  --stop-signal     Signal to stop the container
  --tmpfs           Mount tmpfs to the container at the given path
  -t,--tty          Open a TTY with the container process.
  --ulimit          Ulimit options (format: <name>=<soft>[:<hard>], use -1 for unlimited)
  -u,--user         User ID for the process (name|uid|uid:gid)
  -v,--volume       Bind mount a volume to the container
  -w,--workdir      Working directory inside the container
  -?,--help         Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Starts a container.

Usage: wslc start [<options>] <container-id>

The following arguments are available:
  container-id      Container ID

The following options are available:
  -a,--attach       Attach to stdout/stderr of the container
  -i,--interactive  Attach to stdin and keep it open
  -?,--help         Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Display a snapshot of a running container's resource usage: CPU, memory, network I/O, block I/O, and PIDs.

Usage: wslc stats [<options>] [<container-id>]

The following arguments are available:
  container-id    Container ID

The following options are available:
  -a,--all        Show all regardless of state.
  --format        Output formatting (json or table) (Default: table)
  --no-trunc      Do not truncate output
  -?,--help       Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Stops containers.

Usage: wslc stop [<options>] [<container-id>]

The following arguments are available:
  container-id    Container ID

The following options are available:
  -s,--signal     Signal to send
  -t,--time       Time in seconds to wait before executing (default 5)
  -?,--help       Shows help about the selected command

Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.
For privacy information about this product please visit https://aka.ms/privacy.

Show version information for this tool.

Usage: wslc version [<options>]

The following options are available:
  -?,--help  Shows help about the selected command

